<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbial Systems Biology on Microbial Systems</title>
    <link>https://microbial.systems/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microbial Systems Biology on Microbial Systems</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:19:58 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://microbial.systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alyssa wins 2 undergraduate awards before starting PhD program</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2024-cruz-ph-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 14:19:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2024-cruz-ph-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alyssa Cruz, an outstanding undergraduate researcher in the lab, has won the&amp;hellip; Outstanding Undergraduate in Public Health Award, &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; won a poster award at the 2024 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucdenver.edu/sites/research-day&#34;&gt;CU Denver Research and Creative Activities symposium&lt;/a&gt;.  After graduation this semester, she&amp;rsquo;s headed off to do a PhD at the Sanford Burnham Prebys Medical Discovery Institute.  Congratulations, Alyssa!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microbial.systems/media/Cruz_RaCAS_award.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;image of a poster award certificate&#34; width=&#34;20%&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jessie wins poster award at FRMS</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2024-romero-frms-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 10:39:35 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2024-romero-frms-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our collaborator Jessie Romero here at CU Denver, who won a poster award at this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://frontrangemicrobiomesymposium.com/&#34;&gt;Front Range Microbiome Symposium (FRMS)&lt;/a&gt; for her work on uncovering potential 1,4-dioxane mechanisms in a local bioremediation facility.  Jessie&amp;rsquo;s use of shotgun metagenomics to uncover unique candidate degradation enzymes is a great demonstration of detailed hypothesis generation from high-throughput sequencing technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Lucia for her MS Defense</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-lucia-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 22:04:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-lucia-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Lucia, who defended her MS Thesis today.  Lucia&amp;rsquo;s thesis advanced our ability to predict and annotate plasmid contigs from environmental samples with metagonmic sequencing, and highlighted the strengths and limitations of current tools.  Congratulations, Lucia!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New science education publication</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-mem-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 18:23:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-mem-publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chris contributed to a new publication led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fortlewis.edu/academics/schools-departments/faculty-directory/lee&#34;&gt;Joslynn Lee&lt;/a&gt; at Ft. Lewis College that describes &amp;ldquo;a curriculum and research framework designed to integrate an Indigenous approach when conducting authentic scientific research and to build interest and confidence at the undergraduate level.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;strong&gt;Monitoring environmental microbiomes: Alignment of microbiology and computational biology competencies within a culturally integrated curriculum and research framework&lt;/strong&gt; is published in Molecular Ecology Resources.  Read this important work &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/1755-0998.13867&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Some of the lessons we learned in this project have informed our Biology curriculum here at CU Denver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jessie Romero defends MS thesis on 1,4-dioxane degradation</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-j.romero-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 22:15:31 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2023-j.romero-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are all celebrating Jessie Romero, a collaborator from the Roane lab, for &lt;a href=&#34;https://clas.ucdenver.edu/integrative-biology/2023/11/20/jessica-romero-masters-degree-thesis-defense&#34;&gt;defending her MS Thesis&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Using Metagenomic Sequencing to Elucidate the Bacterial Degradation of 1,4-Dioxane in Groundwater Associated With a Colorado Landfill.&amp;rdquo;  Jessie used metagenomic sequencing to identify several candidate organisms and proteins involved in 1,4-Dioxane degradation.  Her work has opened up a whole new area of research for the lab and our collaborators in the Roane lab to pursue.  Jessie also is the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences Outstanding MS graduate this semester.  Congratulations, Jessie!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Alex on a successful MS Thesis Defense</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-romero-a-thesis-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:59:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-romero-a-thesis-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Alex Romero for a great MS Thesis defense.  Alex&amp;rsquo;s thesis was titled, &amp;ldquo;Characterizing the Gut Microbiome of Golden Retrievers Using Highly Replicated 16s rRNA Sequencing.&amp;rdquo;  Alex did a great job managing a complex project with many challenges, including hurdles brought on by the pandemic.  Congratulations, Alex!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex to share golden retriever microbiome work at World Microbe Forum</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-alex_world_microbe_forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 16:05:18 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-alex_world_microbe_forum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Alex Romero, who had his abstract accepted for poster presentation at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldmicrobeforum.org/&#34;&gt;World Microbe Forum&lt;/a&gt; meeting this summer, and won &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; department travel awards to present at this meeting and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://asm.org/Events/ASM-Conference-for-Undergraduate-Educators/Home&#34;&gt;ASM Conference for Undergraduate Educators&lt;/a&gt; (ASMCUE) (with Andrew McDevitt from Laurel Hartley&amp;rsquo;s group).  We&amp;rsquo;re excited for Alex to present his work on the Golden Retriever gut microbiome and the use of a Course-based Undergraduate Research Experience utilized to help complete this project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kayla awarded EUReCA summer fellowship</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-kayla_eureca_summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 16:02:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-kayla_eureca_summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, Kayla, for being awarded a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucdenver.edu/lynxconnect/undergraduate-research&#34;&gt;EUReCA! Summer Fellows&lt;/a&gt; Award.  This is real $$$ to do real undergraduate research on campus this summer.  Kayla will be helping with additional lab work and analysis of the microbial communities responsible for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucdenver.edu/urban/homepage/2020-award-recipients/establishing-a-mechanistic-understanding-of-how-microbial-communities-remediate-groundwater-pollution-at-an-epa-superfund-site-in-the-denver-metropolitan-area&#34;&gt;1,4 dioxane bioremediation at the Lowry Landfill&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, Lucia</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-welcome-lucia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:09:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2021-welcome-lucia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to have Lucia joining the lab from the Computational Bioscience program, after finishing up her rotation.  Lucia is working on development of bioinformatics algorithms and approaches to improve protein annotation from shotgun metagenomic and other omics data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annarose Phelps wins UROP grant</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-phelps-urop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 14:52:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-phelps-urop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Annarose for being awarded an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucdenver.edu/lynxconnect/undergraduate-research/grants&#34;&gt;Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program (UROP) Mini Grant&lt;/a&gt;.  This competitive grant funds Annarose to continue her research collaborating with the Vajda Lab on the fish gut microbiome upon exposure to environmental toxins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kayla Medina presents at 2020 SACNAS Conference</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-medina-sacnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:25:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-medina-sacnas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kayla Medina is presenting her Undergraduate Research contribution to the Golden Retriever Microbiome project this week at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.2020sacnas.org/&#34;&gt;SACNAS 2020&lt;/a&gt;.  This year&amp;rsquo;s conference is virtual, but Kayla is doing a great job representing the lab&amp;rsquo;s work in this format.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 Urban Research Grant</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-urban-research-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:11:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-urban-research-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to share that we have been funded as part of the initial round of awardees for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucdenver.edu/urban&#34;&gt;CU Denver Presidential Initiative on Urban and Place-Based Research&lt;/a&gt;.  Our project is a collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://clas.ucdenver.edu/integrative-biology/timberley-roane&#34;&gt;Timberley Roane&lt;/a&gt; at CU Denver.  The work will provide a genome-resolved mechanistic understanding of the biochemical metabolisms and microbial community ecosystem interactions that are responsible for 1,4-dioxane remediation at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lowrylandfill.com/&#34;&gt;Lowry Landfill&lt;/a&gt; bioremediation plant.  This site in metro Denver is an important success story for bioremediation, and we hope to gain a mechanistic understanding of this success that improves site management and offers actionable insights for similar sites around the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New DOE award to improve protein annotation</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-doe-annotation-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 16:17:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-doe-annotation-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are very excited and grateful to receive &lt;a href=&#34;https://genomicscience.energy.gov/compbio/2020Awards.shtml&#34;&gt;DOE funding&lt;/a&gt; in order to improve computational biology methods for protein annotation.  Our project will innovate upon and scale up expert curation approaches to create new bioinformatics tools that allow easy-to-use and metabolism-centric protein annotations.  Our world-class collaborators on this project are &lt;a href=&#34;https://cse.ucdenver.edu/~farnoush/&#34;&gt;Farnoush Banaei-Kashani&lt;/a&gt;, at CU Denver Computer Science and Engineering, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wrightonlab.com/&#34;&gt;Kelly Wrighton&lt;/a&gt;, at CSU, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anl.gov/profile/christopher-s-henry&#34;&gt;Chris Henry&lt;/a&gt;, at Argonne National Labs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ucdenver.edu/department-of-energy-awards-1m-to-cu-denver-led-team-for-computational-biology/&#34;&gt;CU Denver press release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maria Nikulkova thesis defense</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-nikulkova-grad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 17:19:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-nikulkova-grad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maria Nikulkova successfully defended her MS thesis today (and gave a great talk).  Maria&amp;rsquo;s thesis is titled, &amp;ldquo;Novel genomes reveal phylogenetic breadth and metabolic insights for the candidate phylum Aenigmarchaeota.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maria is now off to do a PhD at NYU.  Congratulations and best of luck, Maria!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 CU Denver RaCAS</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-racas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 20:09:33 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2020-racas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Annarose Phelps has won 3rd place in the &amp;ldquo;Natural &amp;amp; Physical Sciences&amp;rdquo; category for her RaCAS 2020 poster.  Congratulations, Annarose!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/view/racas2020/award-winners#h.7tdk6gaxirky&#34;&gt;https://sites.google.com/view/racas2020/award-winners#h.7tdk6gaxirky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Annarose and Kayla both put together very nice posters and presentations to represent our work at the CU Denver Research and Creativer Activities Symposium.  It&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be able to present our work in person right now, but both Annarose and Kayla represented our labs  and their science well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New publication on methylotrophic methanogens in freshwater wetlands</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2019-msystems-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 21:46:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2019-msystems-pub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Narrowe, A.B., Borton, M.A., Hoyt, D.W., Smith, G.J., Daly, R.A., Angle, J.C., Eder, E.K., Wong, A.R., Wolfe, R.A., Pappas, A., Bohrer, G., Miller, C.S. &amp;amp; Wrighton, K.C., 2019. Uncovering the Diversity and Activity of Methylotrophic Methanogens in Freshwater Wetland Soils W. Orsi, ed. mSystems, 4(6), pp.e00320-19. &lt;a href=&#34;https://msystems.asm.org/content/4/6/e00320-19&#34;&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study uses field work, laboratory microcosms, and multiple types of omics data to gain new insights into how methylotrophic methanogens contribute to carbon cycling in the Old Woman Creek freshwater wetlands.  This is another publication stemming from our fantastic collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wrightonlab.com/&#34;&gt;Wrighton Lab&lt;/a&gt; at CSU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maria presents our work at ASM 2019</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2019-nikulkova-asm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 13:14:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2019-nikulkova-asm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maria Nikulkova is presenting her work this week on some new Aenigmarchaeota genomes at the American Society for Microbiology annual meeting (ASM Microbe).  She also was awarded the ASM Capstone Research Fellowship this year!  With this award, Maria gets her travel to present her poster at the ASM Microbe meeting covered, and will participate in the ASM Microbe Academy for Professional Development.  Congratulations, Maria!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New publication utilizing metagenomic data for understanding the evolution of translation</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/ef-2-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 15:23:35 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/ef-2-pub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/gbe/article/10/9/2380/5060531&#34;&gt;Complex evolutionary history of translation Elongation Factor 2 and diphthamide biosynthesis in Archaea and parabasalids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the product of a great collaboration with some excellent labs and people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diphthamide is a modified histidine residue which is uniquely present in archaeal and eukaryotic elongation factor 2 (EF-2), an essential GTPase responsible for catalyzing the coordinated translocation of tRNA and mRNA through the ribosome. In part due to the role of diphthamide in maintaining translational fidelity, it was previously assumed that diphthamide biosynthesis genes (dph) are conserved across all eukaryotes and archaea. Here, comparative analysis of new and existing genomes reveals that some archaea (i.e., members of the Asgard superphylum, Geoarchaea, and Korarchaeota) and eukaryotes (i.e., parabasalids) lack dph. In addition, while EF-2 was thought to exist as a single copy in archaea, many of these dph-lacking archaeal genomes encode a second EF-2 paralog missing key-residues required for diphthamide modification and for normal translocase function, perhaps suggesting functional divergence linked to loss of diphthamide biosynthesis. Interestingly, some Heimdallarchaeota previously suggested to be most closely related to the eukaryotic ancestor maintain dph genes and a single gene encoding canonical EF-2. Our findings reveal that the ability to produce diphthamide, once thought to be a universal feature in archaea and eukaryotes, has been lost multiple times during evolution, and suggest that anticipated compensatory mechanisms evolved independently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduation 2018</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/graduation-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 16:27:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/graduation-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lab feels like it’s emptying out, with 1 PhD, 1 MS, and 2 BS graduates this May. Congratulations to:&#xA;Dr. Adrienne Narrowe, PhD (with both the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences and the Department of Integrative Biology outstanding Defense awards)&#xA;David Banks-Richardson, MS Biology&#xA;Maria Nikulkova, BS Biology&#xA;Connor Jacobs, BS Biology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A great accomplishment for each of them, and the whole lab can’t wait to see what each accomplishes next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New freshwater wetlands / methane publication</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-natcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:32:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-natcom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Old Woman Creek Wetlands team has a new publication out revealing that much of the methane in this wetland appears to come from a novel methanogen residing in surface, oxygenated soils.  Congratulations and thanks to the Wrighton and Bohrer labs, who led this work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Angle, J.C., Morin, T.H., Solden, L.M., Narrowe, A.B., Smith, G.J., Borton, M.A., Rey-Sanchez, C., Daly, R.A., Mirfenderesgi, G., Hoyt, D.W., Riley, W.J., Miller, C.S., Bohrer, G. &amp;amp; Wrighton, K.C., 2017. Methanogenesis in oxygenated soils is a substantial fraction of wetland methane emissions. Nature Communications, 8(1), p.1567.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations, Mallika</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-iyer-grad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 16:34:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-iyer-grad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Mallika, who successfully defended her MS Thesis, “Prediction of Prokaryotic Optimum Growth Temperature Based on Genomic And Proteomic Features.”  Mallika did a great job, showing her mastery of her research and the literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mallika is off to the Burnham Institute to pursue her PhD with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bioinformatics.burnham.org/pages/&#34;&gt;Adam Godzik&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And the award goes to…</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-narrowe-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 16:38:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-narrowe-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2017 Integrative Biology Outstanding Graduate Student of the Year:&#xA;Adrienne Narrowe!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, Adrienne.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://microbial.systems/media/narrowe_outstanding.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kendra DeHay, MS</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-dehay-grad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 17:13:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-dehay-grad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratualtions to Master of Science Kendra DeHay, graduating from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20180901152653/https://gs.ucdenver.edu/biotech/&#34;&gt;Master’s Program in Biomedical Sciences &amp;amp; Biotechnology&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PhD-Bound</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-phd-bound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 17:15:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-phd-bound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Mallika and to Nihal!  Both are headed to do great things in great PhD programs.  Mallika will be joining &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20180901152653/http://bioinformatics.burnham.org/pages/&#34;&gt;Adam Godzik’s group at the Sanford Burnham Prebys Medical Discovery Institute&lt;/a&gt;, and Nihal is joining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20180901152653/https://www.inp.uci.edu/&#34;&gt;UC Irvine Interdepartmental Neuroscience Program&lt;/a&gt;.  Each program is lucky to have an exceptional student.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New publication describing archaea in freshwater wetlands</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-em-pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 17:16:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2017-em-pub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our publication describing the unexplored archaeal diversity in the Old Woman Creek freshwater wetland has been accepted to Environmental Microbiology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20180901152653/http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1462-2920.13703/abstract&#34;&gt;High-resolution sequencing reveals unexplored archaeal diversity in freshwater wetland soils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This research, which was led by Adrienne, results from work done with our great collaborators in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wrightonlab.com/&#34;&gt;Wrighton Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adrienne gets her DDIG funded</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2016-narrowe-ddig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 17:19:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2016-narrowe-ddig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Adrienne, who just received word that her NSF Doctoral Dissertation Improvement Grant will be recommended for funding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome, Kendra</title>
      <link>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2016-welcome-dehay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 17:23:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microbial.systems/lab-news/2016-welcome-dehay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lab welcomes Kendra DeHay.  Kendra is a student in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gs.ucdenver.edu/biotech/&#34;&gt;Master’s Program in Biomedical Sciences &amp;amp; Biotechnology&lt;/a&gt;.  She is working on the Golden Retriever Microbiome project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
